you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Applause]
[Music]
Tesla hello everyone and welcome back to
the AI native Dev and hot and heels of
our last episode we're back chat with
bala knous welcome Bala thank you s this
is a followup on the previous chat that
we had and we're actually going to go
handson we're going to screen share and
we're going to show how code can be
generated from basically some tdd style
tests whereby we're writing tests in
advance generating code from those tests
and then validating that the code is
doing what we expect effectively the
tests are forming somewhat of a
specification for our component or our
application we're going to start fairly
simple and then jump into more of a real
world application but Bala tell us a
little bit more about the style the way
of working in which your your process is
going to take here yes I will currently
on the screen a little flow diagram and
on the left we have the tests those are
the things we WR as humans provide those
tests to gen we give them to gen we ask
them to come up with an implementation
that will pass this test then we move to
the middle box which implementation so
the Gen gave us an implementation then
we run the test against it
implementation if all tests pass we have
production already code as you can see
in the schema there are two Loops let's
start with a small Loop and the Gen we
ask J to come up with an implementation
but sometimes it doesn't really listen
and it comes up with an explanation and
we cannot run tests against an
explanation and sometimes J comes up
with non-c compiling code that's also a
problem so we ask it again and until we
get a proper implementation that comp
pass then sometimes not all tests pass
then we follow the no Arrow from test
pass we extract the errors from the test
that do not pass and we feed them back
to J and we ask gen to come up with a
better implementation in which all test
will pass both Loops get five iterations
and normally that's more than enough but
sometimes it's not enough and then it
says I cannot find an implementation for
this test okay cool in terms of to be
showing this working from a fairly
simple OD even test going up more
complex for this tell us a little bit
about some of the technologies that
we're using are you using a local model
today or are you going to be in the
cloud yeah very good question I always
start off with a local model so I'm
using a tool called AMA ol Lama is like
the docker for large language models
local large language models and it works
pretty fine we're going to use llama 3.1
that's the one model I'm using recently
and that's the one model that works best
for this use case if the local llama 3.1
model isn't capable of solving the
problem we will move to a cloud llm
because the cloud lims are yeah just
better yeah okay cool I I guess there's
a third flow here if we are you know
following of a true tdd model we write
certain tests let it generate and then
iterate on that ourselves we might write
another test and another test um is is
that the way you envisage this to to
work and once you hit done you go back
and then there's another iteration on
this to say actually now let's add that
next bit of functionality and get some
failing tests that we try and get pass
in with the new
implementation yeah that's how it works
so in the old days when we didn't do
this when you would like to add
functionality you would just add more
code and then preferably add first test
and add more code but now in this idea
you're not allowed to touch the
implementation anymore so if you want to
add your feature you add more tests
rerun the tool until we get to the done
stage so we have work impation that will
also pass the new test yeah okay cool
and I guess when there's a test failing
we as developers want to have a look at
the test and go straight to the code and
take a look at that ourselves do you
still fall into that tra or do you just
say oh go on do it a few more times and
then let's see if you can do it yeah so
in the beginning I did also because I
wasn't sure if the tool I'm going to
show up worked properly right and
nowadays I'll just leave it to the AI
there still there will be every time
when I run the tool there will be file
called generator. log and you can can
see all the steps that the tool take you
can also see which test failed you can
see what the new prompt is for the Gen
you can I use it as dbook tool if
something goes wrong with the tool I can
see what happened why didn't it work as
extended but for people just starting
this tool it's really interesting to see
what was happening what was going wrong
because that still happens so yeah it
becomes less and less once you get used
to this way of working yeah gotcha okay
let's jump in What don't we start with
the uneven test and I think you going be
using chat GPT for this generate the
code right yeah correct so I would like
to start really simple I would like to
start with an OD even test this is Java
I use Java because that's the language
I'm most familiar with but for people
who do not know NAA no problem if you
know any other programming language out
there you should be capable of following
along so we have a test and what we're
going to test is OD even so we expect an
object to be called OD even and we
expected to have a method called is even
now we all know if you provide
even numbers to an is even method it
should return true if we provide uneven
numbers it should provide false so this
is the test case to we going to give to
the AI for now we're going to do
everything manually I'm going to copy
this going to go to Jet GPT I'm going to
ask it please
provide an
implementation that passes this test and
I'm going to paste the code over here
and press enter
the idea is that jet GPT comes up with
an implementation now first you get some
interesting text and then we can just
copy the code pretty difficult to copy
If It Moves so it's copied oh it's in
Dutch now it doesn't matter we go over
here we go to the file that should be
tested so the test subject notice that I
have a dummy implementation which always
returns false this is incorrect I'm
going to copy uh select everything paste
the code from jgpt here I go back to the
test I run the test and I hope
everything becomes green as you can see
over here we have a green test jet GPT
was capable of brighten and
implementation that passes this test I
wonder if we was to change the ad evens
and the is even to be something that
doesn't refer to the word even and same
with the odd even test sorry odd even
and is even do you feel like it would
have done the mod uh too or do you feel
like it would have hardcoded those those
responses so effectively said if it's
zero do this if it's two do this yeah
very good question actually I tried that
I did the same test and I removed all
recognizable words I I so this would
become an a test this would become B
this would become C so there were no
human readable words bit logic in there
the meaning in there it still is capable
of coming up with a solution yeah but
I'm pretty sure it helps yeah the right
words gives more input for the AI to
come up with the right implementation
yeah yeah we can do we can go script and
do a little test right now I don't know
how much time you want to yeah let's do
let's go script let's yeah let's go of
script let's see what happens nothing
bad happens when you go script
right so we're going to change this into
a test and we're going to change this in
B test going to change this
into
C we going to yeah let's do
everything so now it's C and we're going
to change this
in a method so there's oh and maybe we
should change the package as well let's
do that as well shif
six what does it ask yeah let's do
everything and then I say
package okay I don't think there is any
recognizable what happens if we do this
so I'm GNA copy this go to Jet GPT let's
do a clean context yeah I was ask the
other one right so that's this one
please provide an
implementation that
FES and I'm going to paste anonymized
code no more references to other even
exactly the same and look at that it
already sees yep odd numbers yeah so so
it notice and it comes up with a proper
solution as well yeah yeah so yeah I can
run it but this will work and of course
and and of course not that it
understands this code or understands
what you're trying to do but there are
patterns of tests and implementations
that testing for 2 468 and
1357 and that's how it's that's how it's
matching that pattern but it's
absolutely if if you was to add odd and
even in the test as well it will infer
that's what you're trying to do and and
make it easier to to pattern match but
that's nice test we should we go back to
that script yeah let's go back to the
script first I'll show a really simple
OD even test then we showed you it
doesn't need a worse OD even it can
still generate but let's take something
more complex and do exactly the same and
the thing that I prepared is prime
number generation so we have a test over
here and it's pretty simple so again a
test called under 50 we expect there to
be an object called prime number
generator or a class I should say it has
one method called generate you provided
a number which is the upper bound of the
prime numbers to generate and if you
provided 50 we expect those prime
numbers to be generated right so we copy
this again we go to jgpt new
context please provide an
implementation that passes this test
again I'm going to paste it and we're
going to wait for the answer um the
answer will be more complex this time so
we're not going to spend too much time
on it we're just going to copy it once
we can so let's see when it's finished
it's a bit slow this morning there it is
so now I can copy the code go back to my
IDE let's go to the test subject this Dy
implementation returns null which is
incorrect going to select everything I'm
going to paste the code back to my test
select everything and let's run it to
see what
happens and as you can see we have a
green check mark So jet GPT was capable
of coming up with a prime number
generator by just providing this test
let's take a look at the code though
yeah we can that's totally fine but yeah
we can really deep dive in this but I'm
not really good at I don't know how it
actually I don't know there are all kind
of algorithms to do this and I probably
this is not the best one I don't even
really understand it do you how is your
math gosh yeah yeah so but that's why we
have test for and this is also the idea
behind this way of working you don't
need to know how it's implemented if you
test you trust your implementation so
yeah yeah that looks right actually so
it's checking it's essentially checking
if if everything less than if every
number less than that number when modded
equals zero so if there's no remainder
yeah do you ask me do you go back to the
implementation no I don't yeah I want I
was curious I was
curious but at a given moment it's okay
cool I'm really happy with this we now I
I have proven that the concept works
right so we can write Tes self we can
give it to an AI Andi will come up with
an implementation so this works so I'm
pretty happy but there are two big
issues with this approach and the first
one is the fact that there are too many
manual steps I had to copy code from my
IDE to my browser wait till it generated
copy it from the browser back to my IDE
Cod to the test subject paste it back to
the test run it so far too many manual
steps so I decided to automate this
because that's what we do as developers
right if we have to do too many manual
things we become unhappy and we going to
automate things so I created a tool that
does this for you so let's do exactly
the same but now with a tool and the
tool is just a simple jarf fall it's
over here it's in a different directory
but you can just call it and what we
have to provide it we have to provide
the tool with a path to a test F let's
take the prime number thingy so this
test I'm going to copy the PA and I'm
going to paste it over here and I'm
going to press enter so the tool starts
up I told you we have two Loops we have
a test Loop to see if all test BS and we
have a code loop to ask the AI to come
up for
code and currently it's talking to a
local llm running on my machine llama
3.1 as you can see there is an
implementation there is a test and all
test pass now let's see what it came up
with so so the code loot there is really
just trying to loop around until it has
something which is test worthy which is
B which is essentially can it compile so
this is the code loop and this is the
test yeah and then the test Loop is
really
will the tests pass now it's compiled
running yep as you can see this's a
different
diation um no square root there is some
multiplication in there but this you so
I did exactly the same but now I just I
run a tool I grab a cup of coffee I come
back and I have a working
implementation this is so much more nice
you don't have to do all the manual
steps anymore while having this now we
have a tool so now we can easily provide
test and wait for the AI to come up with
Solutions all the demos I give up till
now I tried to create something new but
developers all have written hundreds or
maybe a thousand tests in their life you
can also use this tool on existing tests
and that's what I did actually I used
the tool to improve the tool let me show
you a little bit so in the tool is
something called a code container and
the code container has multiple features
first of all it holds the code that is
provided by the large language model
secondly this is we do all this in Java
and if you know a little bit about Java
in Java the name of a file should be
equal to the name of the class this is a
class so this file this class called
prime number generator should be in a
file called prime number generator those
should be the same so one of the
features of the code container is to
extract the file name from the code
another feature that uh the code
container has it should be capable of
extracting the package because in Java
if you use a package the F the folder
structure on your file system should be
equal to this package structure so this
file should be in orc example prime
number and look at that orc example
prime number so this code container has
those features I created of course test
for that so let's start with the first
test the first one we'll try to extract
the file name from code so we have a
little bit of code over here now this is
pretty simple the file name that I
expect is Happy flow. Java right now I
have all kinds of tests here I put the
random spes and spots we have classes we
have public classes and you see all the
answers and also notice that I added
messages we talked about does the AI uh
take cues from the wording that you use
I use those messages specifically to
instruct the AI because if a test fails
I feedback this message and ask for a
new implementation so even without AIS I
think it's a good practice to add
messages but this also really helps the
AI to come up with a better solution so
understands better what goes wrong yeah
and and this helps otherwise otherwise
there's going to be more human
interaction on this right because as
soon as something fails you need to then
instruct why it's failed but if you're
doing this in a more automated way it's
it's a nice Loop that doesn't need a
human interaction yeah now we do
something similar for package name
extraction so you see packages over here
little classes so this one should return
happy flow again we have spaces in uh
different spots and notice that I have
multi-level packages over here and
notice that I have no package over here
because package is optional and then
again the messages so those are this is
the test that I Ed to test my
implementation and now I have a
confession to make I made a really
crappy implementation if you know a
little bit about programming you know
you can easily solve this with regular
Expressions but yeah I'm pretty bad at
those so I started out with a really
crappy string manipulation solution and
I hoped when feeding this to the tool it
would come up with a better
implementation that I could then use in
the tool so let's see what happens I
need this puff I go over here I remove
the last parameter and I paste the path
see that it ends with code container
test and now I'm asking the local model
to come up with an implementation that
passes the test that you see on top and
this is already a much more complicated
problem than the problems we talked
about before let's see what if it can do
it in one shot also while we're waiting
let's introduce the generator. log this
is what I use for debugging you can see
I'm using 3.1 something happened so
there was an implementation it found two
test it ran the test against the
implementation but zero of the tests
succeeded so now we feed back to the AI
those two tests failed please come up
with a better implementation and it's
retry now if you look over here you see
the prompt is pretty elaborate your
professional Java developer give me a
single file complete Java implementation
that will pass this test do not respond
with the test sometimes that happens
give me only complete code no Snippets
include Imports and use the right
package and as you can see we get a time
out I use a time out of 30 seconds and
the local model wasn't didn't seem to be
able to solve it now the first thing
that you do like every developer you
retry right y course something we
already did but especially with large
language models they always come up with
something different there's like a
fussiness in there you retry yeah if in
the second attempt the local model
cannot handle it notice that we already
have something better once passes yeah
and when I practice with this I also use
those test those demos for presentations
at conferences normally the local model
is capable of solving this but if it
isn't capable of solving it we will
switch to a cloud model yeah
but hey look at that hey go it improved
first we had one success again one
success but now we have two successes so
let's see what it came up with so here's
the test let's go back to the test
subject and as you can see for the
people who know yaa regex regular
expressions and it came up with two
regular Expressions that can extract the
file name and extract the package name
so you can use this tool to improve your
existing code if you already have tests
lying
around any question about that Simon I I
I find this really interesting because
when you think about that first test we
did the simpler test there are going to
be there there are going to be examples
of an odd even or even a prime number
all over the place right because it's
like one of those things that people try
just to just to start encoding so you'd
think it would be easier for for AI to
be able to find an example of that with
this though it's slightly different
because this isn't something that you
would expect to find everywhere this is
much more specific to what we're trying
which I guess is why it took in this
case three attempts but it's still very
impressive that it looked at its Rex and
trying was trying to I'm talking about
it like it's actually doing this
understand what was going wrong and how
it could actually change it and it's all
again it's all correlation and pattern
matching but and token matching but but
it's mind-blowing that it can do this in
just a few attempts and and one of the
reasons why it's so useful is I think as
a developer you solve different problems
every day but yeah probably 99% of
problems that you have solved are
already solved many times by other
developers yeah or similar
enough different the variable names are
different but yeah in and if you boil it
down probably somebody else has already
solved it so most problems should be
solvable this way now one other question
actually in terms of when you go through
the iterations and you have the number
of different attempts obviously we can
alter temperature of of various models
to increase the chances of a
hallucination which may actually make it
more creative and identify more
interesting Solutions and actually on
the podcast previously there's trainer
was talking about how if you increase
the temperature of their of their chat
bot Finn if you increase the temperature
you're more likely to be successful with
a greater number of requests however
there is a greater chance of it
effectively just talking and
creating things that are just not true
and the question was how comfortable are
you with that balance now I feel like
sometimes if it is continually failing
here increase in temperature is not
going to be too big a deal because you
still have tests which is validating
that and it's much harder to validate
some written text and it is something
which needs to be syntactically true or
false do you play with the temperature
at all in your models or is that
something that makes a difference I get
this question a lot actually I don't
play with it I find that the one they
use by default works pretty well but I
would like to add something you just
said there's a factor we didn't talk
about yet and that's costs yeah cly I'm
running this against my local llm so the
costs are pretty minimalistic of course
my laptop will the the battery will die
sooner so my electric bill will be a
little bit higher at the end of the
month but probably will not notice it
once you start using Cloud large
language models that's a different story
so let me give you a little bit of
example I created this tool which
involved calling those Cloud ones pretty
much I practice I give it at conferences
and meetups so I've been using this for
let's say eight months and I spent about
10 at jgpt MH so playing around with it
is not that expensive yeah but if you
you're going to use this for every test
case that you have I think it will
become pretty pricey pretty soon but on
the other hand the models are getting
better they get faster and they getting
cheaper so we are in a time I I see a
future in which this is
feasible picture this you write your
test you run the tool you get your
coffee you come back if the tool worked
you save probably hours yeah and for the
cost of a cup of coffee yeah so yeah why
not try it I get I get a coffee yeah
yeah and even better if it failed the
tool it cost you a little bit of money
but you still have to test then you do
the old fashioned way you still write
the implementation yourself right yeah
you don't lose a lot or you look at
where's going wrong that makes you think
about the implementation I'm pretty sure
afterwards you will write a better
implementation about the
implementation actually there are no
Downs out except for the little money
part yeah yeah okay so let's jump
forward yeah so you asked me how do you
add features let's do a little bit
little about we have the prime number
generator test and what I'm going to do
I'm going to add a test that what I want
is when you provide a negative number
over here it should throw an exception
because we don't know negative prime
numbers so let's do that so what I'm
going to do I'm just going to add a test
over here and I'm going to say
public V
negative
input and then we need to now we need
now let let me first do something else
we're going to use something from junit
is called assert throws it asserts if
something is thrown so like this the
first thing that you have to provide is
what kind of exception do you want
runtime exception sounds fine to me and
then you provide a Lambda think like
this and then you
say huh I'm missing something that me I
need this so thank you did you see what
happened there was the on line code
completion from intell which is pretty
pretty fantastic is that using the
intellig assistant or is that using no
this the I don't pay for the jet brain
AIS and this is just a free one okay and
do you see what's on my screen this
exactly what I want but I only typed the
pr so it in first from the context what
I want which is already pretty great let
me see did I do this
correctly I'm not sure if I did this
correctly let me now let's run it let's
see what happens let's first run the
test to see if the test
runs wrong button sorry for
that yeah so you see under 50 still
works but negative doesn't work because
it doesn't throw run this code isn't
there yet right y now now I'm going to
run exactly the same command as I did
before so not the code container but the
prime number generator so I did not
change the prompt so the only thing
that's different is that currently the
file contains two test cases instead of
one test case and we expected now to
update the codes so also the
second test case you see it too find a
solution let's go to the implementation
and I think this is the new part
and this is how you add
features to your implementation just
write more tests that specify the
features that you
want questions no this looks awesome and
it's really it's that tdd way it's that
it will do the minimum it requires to
make those tests pass and I think your
code is as good as your tests here right
it's really tightly coupled yeah yeah
yeah I'm really happy with this tool but
one problem one problem left one big
problem actually and that's the fact
that it's pretty good at generating
plain Java code and that's what we did
up till now but if we at our daily job
we use libraries we use Frameworks and
the tool in its current form cannot use
those it doesn't know about spring boot
it doesn't know about quarkus and it's
pretty difficult because it only input
is a test case how can it extract from
this test case which libraries or
Frameworks you're using so I started
thinking about this problem and actually
did the solution is pretty simple we
have to create we have to do something
with your build system for Java that is
normally Maven or Gradle I have far more
experience with Maven and I have with
cradle therefore I created a maven
plugin and if you do that if you have a
maven plugin you can easily access all
your libraries and so for the tool I
created a ma plugin that creates a
custom class loader that loads all the
dependencies and then it can come up
with working code when you're
using libraries or Frameworks so let me
show you how it works so the compiling
part should be should know about the
libraries that it uses got it the P XML
so I there's a lot of stuff in P XML the
most important part is this I created a
new plugin it's called the test driven
generation Maven plugin and its most
important part is the configuration part
and like with the jar file we have to
provide a path to test file now notice
that there is a test file already over
here and it says end Point test let me
show you the endpoint
test so over here so this is a really
simple spring boot hello world example
now for people who are unfamiliar with
spring boot this is how you create a
spring boot test normally works with a
random Port which is initialized over
here not really important this is
important we have a rest template we use
this to do a rest call as you can see
over here we do a get on the root of
Local Host and then at random port and
if we do this get we expected to say
hello world but this is a spring boot so
it has to come up with a spring boot
solution and the tools should be capable
over running the spring boot Solution
that's why we need the ma plugin y so
did I point out everything I want to
point out I think I did let's try try it
so let's go we need use we need to use
maen you do this like this test driven
typo
generation generate so this will
run this plugin I talked about before
and of course this plugin just reuses
jarfile and you recognize this output
you've seen this before when we were
using the jarf fall and now it's talking
to the local LM and it asked llm to come
up with an implementation that passes
this test so we want a spring boot
application that returns hello world
when you do a get on the root URL now as
you can see things are going wrong as
expected so we're feeding back the
errors to the large language model and
we ask it to come up with better
implementations there is an
implementation here but the test didn't
suceed so we keep waiting and
waiting what's interesting here is that
it's for the first time it's looping
around the code loop and and it's
because it's a much more complex spring
application that needs to be built to
actually satisfy this yeah so this is
much more difficult it looks running
everybody yeah see build success wow
nice let's see let's see what it created
probably let me update
this yeah there it is endpoint
application so it's a spring boot
application now people know spring boot
is is default it is a rest controller a
gap mapping on rout returns hello world
this is exactly what I would write when
people would ask me to write this yeah
so this is pretty cool so let's see if
we can make it a little bit more complex
but you have questions first yeah I do
have a question in terms of so obviously
this is we're getting to that state now
where the a where the GPT is
effectively going to have a greater
number of attempts on the code creation
the more complex we get the greater
those numbers of attempts are going to
be and we're we're going to be more
likely to hit our timeouts or a a retry
limit when when you iterate through for
example if we in fact let's use that
previous example when you added that uh
feature to the prime number test have
you tried using the existing code AS
context to effectively say look this is
the code that I had that ran my previous
test check out my updated tests you need
to update my existing code so that it
effectively adds the functionality
required to pass the failing test
essentially so I guess it comes down to
a little bit more of a tdd style where
it might say let's use the existing code
let's run my test understand what is
failing and then write some additional
codes to to fix that failing test is
that something you've done or considered
so your question is does the second run
know about the first run right know
about the or or even know about the code
in the previous iteration where that
that could even be before that could
even be before youve run this the
previous time you oh sorry ah okay so
your question yeah but in all my
examples right now there is no pre we
always start from scratch right um the
prime number one we just added that new
functionality right so we added the
throw run time and I think we're going
to build upon the spring application as
well so rather than go through those
errors again and actually have more
chance of hitting that retry limit could
we actually say look this is the
previous code that passed the previous
test this is the change I making can you
almost uh adapt or iterate from this
starting point yeah no I did not do that
it is on my to-do list because I think
the tool would become so much better if
it knows more context the more context
you give it the better it results will
be but on the other hand what is there
is when you if you have multiple Loops
it knows about the previous Loops it it
knows what it did before yeah so there
is a little bit of context in there but
not not the entire context over here
that would be like the next Generation
right just nowadays the token window of
the Lang become bigger and bigger so you
can just put your entire project in
there and I think it will really improve
the the hit rate it will really make the
tool even more useful y yeah cool more
questions no good let's move let's move
on yeah I think we're going to update
the the spring go to the the last
example and maybe we can go off script
afterwards something harder but the
thing that I prepared is the following
one so I have an endpoint h test and the
idea here is again spring boot program
we provide it with a a birth date and it
should calculate the age so let me walk
you through the examples if you were
born on the 1 of January this year
you're zero 1 of January of 20120 or
four 1 of January 2000 or 24 but if
you're born on the last day of 2000
you're 23 so this is the difficult part
right that's dep that's depressing isn't
it b a date a birth dat on in 200000 in
the age is 23 24 you old it makes me
feel old yeah makes me feel makes me
feel like I need to go and have a nap
maybe
yeah I I I totally
agree that we uh we expect to do again
on Local Host renom P again and then the
birthday should be part of the URL so we
expect slage SL birth dat and and then
we expect it to return the H so let's
see what happens if we feed this
actually I I I played with this and and
and it couldn't solve the problem it
couldn't solve the problem because I
made a mistake in the input yeah I
switched up those two numbers you know I
was gonna ask that question actually
when we were back in the when we were
trying to trick the uh the LM at the
very very start by changing the method
names and the class names Etc from OD
even I wonder if you to actually change
maybe instead of two have one there
instead I wonder if it would have
thought would have looked at it and
thought do you know what there's enough
tests here to do a mod 2 that it would
pass or it looks it close enough to a
not even but yeah another conversation
perhaps yeah yeah so let's try this and
let's move from there I need no let's go
to the pum
file and so instead of an endpoint test
this one is called endpoint h test and
I'm going to rerun it to see what
happens and I think this is a fairly
complex problem I think if I had to code
it myself it would take me at least 50
minutes maybe more let's see if the
local large language models are capable
of solving this again let's take a look
at the Lock we're still using the local
one Lama 3.1 the time out is 30 seconds
uh you see there in the second code
attempt so the first attempt delivered
no code or at least not code That
Couldn't compile let's see if we can
find something interesting in here let
me reload it let me see what happens so
we see this is what I provided it came
up with something apparently it doesn't
compile I'm not sure why did this didn't
compile then it came up with a second
implementation but that didn't pass the
test so we ask it again come up with
something that passes the test if I look
at this it looks pretty okay I'm not
sure what's wrong here is aging years is
along and it looks like it wants to I
know string value of yeah but this is
also wrong it copied the test in here ah
yeah it's
always so now we're looking into the
depth of what it's doing actually you
don't want to do that you just want
passing test right yeah we' be drinking
our coffee somewhere yeah yeah now I
should get got some coffee but that
probably wouldn't be so interesting for
the users yeah no it's just tuing along
yeah and now you also understand why I'm
using 30 seconds because you don't want
to wait too long especially when you're
doing demos yeah but I think this is a
pretty pretty hard one I would say in
the beginning of the year 5% of the
times that I did this test it was
capable of solving it with a local llm
normally I had to go to Cloud one yeah
nowadays with llama 3.1 I would say it's
capable of solving this problem 50% of
the time this is is taking me too long I
I'm a little bit impatient so I'm going
to prepare for running against the cloud
Alum okay let's go there and what we're
going to do you as you can see there are
all kind of properties over here let's
use entropic you can use J GPT or you
can use entropic right now I'm planning
on adding more models as you can see
something went wrong no solution found
so let's uncomment this let's rerun it
so instead of going to my local llm it
now goes to the cloud llm let me show
you that it's true you can see now it
goes to entropic it's using Cloud 35
sunet now you see directly the
difference something is happening build
success yeah wow straight away look at
that so the is that first time yeah
first time so the local ones are pretty
impressive but the cloud ones are so
much better so let's see what it created
see where did it put it so it's an endo
h calculator I don't I see it should be
over here right ah there there it is
spring boot application rest controller
start spring boot application this is
what I told you it should use a slh and
then the birth date it uses a p varable
for this thing which is correct it
parses it with an ISO date which is
correct it uses today it uses the
difference between today and the
provided part date and it extracts years
this is fantastic this is what I would
write yeah and and it did it in five
seconds yeah yeah um yeah yeah I think I
need more complex and what's what I love
about this is the fact that you are
effectively starting with the validation
so as this gets more complex we are able
to rely on this code much much more
because we start with the tests and we
know the assertion
validated by the end of it yeah this is
awesome yeah and I think the validation
part is the really that is the
interesting part of this approach yeah
so you have a way to validate the output
of your large language model and the the
Air Canada example showed you how
important it is it's going to become
more and more important in the future
because people will keep making this
mistake over and get Burns it will cost
a lot of money but now for coding we
have a way to check which I think is
really cool yeah I know this is the last
demo can folks have a play with this
themselves yeah they can I will after
this I will give to you Simon four links
the first link will be this project
called the AI native Dev example so
people can play with that I will send a
link to the repo that contains a code
that creates a jarfile then a link to
the repo that creates the M plugin so I
will send those to you and if you put
them somewhere yeah we'll put that in
the description in the show notes as
well so absolutely absolutely perfect
thank you we're pretty much at times
Bala this has been super insightful
awesome to chat and awesome to awesome
to throw some off-script challenges at
you as well so thank you thank you very
much and appreciate the appreciate the
session yeah thank you for having me
thank you for the the fact that I could
show off my uh proof Concept in this
area I love to talk to you and I also
really like the upscript one those are
the
best wonderful thanks very much and for
everyone listening uh please tune in to
the next session thank you byebye
[Applause]
[Music]
thanks for tuning in join us next time
on the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla
[Applause]
[Music]